# PAUL FRANZ

CREATIVE AND TECHNICAL DIRECTOR

#### CONTACT

**Email**: paulkfranz@gmail.com **Phone**: +1 202 . 631 . 0218 **Portfolio:** paul-franz.com

• • •

#### **SKILLS**

- Video production and editing
- Motion design and animation
- Front-end web development
- Integrated team management
- Highcharts and D3
- CARTO, MapBox, LeafletJS
- Command line and Git
- Web content management
- DIY computer assembly and hardware knowledge
- I know the correct pronunciation of GIF

• • •

### **EDUCATION**

## M.A. IN MULTIMEDIA JOURNALISM

University of Miami, Fla. – January 2011

## B.A. IN HISTORY AND POLITICAL SCIENCE

Millersville University, Pa. – May 2007

#### **PROFILE**

I am a multi-talented producer with four years of experience in integrated team management and ten years of experience in video production, multimedia, and web development. I work across disciplines and am eager to shape a strategic vision as well as bridge the gap between creative and technical fields.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### ANDREAS C. DRACOPOULOS CHAIR IN CREATIVITY AND INNOVATION

CENTER FOR STRATEGIC AND INT'L STUDIES (CSIS) • NOV 2016 TO PRESENT

- Shape the top-level creative and technical vision of the department;
- Serve as primary creative and technical mentor for staff of ten producers, designers, and web developers;
- Won a \$5 million grant to continue funding support for initiative over five years;
- Built internal agency from two producers;
- Evangelize the work of the department to non-technical stakeholders at conferences and public engagements.

#### **DIRECTOR OF TECHNOLOGY AND MULTIMEDIA**

CSIS • NOV 2013 TO NOV 2016

- Direct all visual storytelling efforts
- Kickstarted first campaign and issue-based microsites

### **MULTIMEDIA PRODUCER**

CSIS • NOV 2012 TO NOV 2013

Produced and designed 3-5 minute motion graphic narratives

#### **MULTIMEDIA PRODUCER AND REPORTER**

EDUCATION WEEK (EPE) • JUNE 2011 TO NOV 2012

- Introduced motion design to organization's storytelling efforts
- Led 2012 election themed coverage with motion and original video

#### **VIDEO/MOTION GRAPHICS INTERN**

TIME MAGAZINE • JAN 2011 TO JUNE 2011

Produced weekly online video talk shows and original video